Here, I'll be talking about a minor seven flat five chord.
Which is also known as a half diminished chord.
Let's look at the scale and I'll show you why.
Here's the major scale, all seven notes.
Now, we're going to first talk about minor seven.
Which we did in the last clip.
Which was a lowered third to make it minor and a lowered seven to make it seven.
You had a one flat, three five, flat seven, for minor seven.
Now we're also going to flat the five.
So you have one, flat three, flat five, flat seven.
Now originally in, we were talking about Triads in part one.
A chord with a one flat three and flat five, was called diminished.
This is called half diminished.
Because to make it a fully diminished chord, you'd also have to lower the seven, a second time.
On the key board, this will be one, three, five, seven.
We're going to lower the third for minor.
The seven for flat seven.
Or maybe the flat seven to make it a seven chord.
And lower the five to make it a flat five or a diminished chord on the bottom with a flat seven on the top.
Now two ways, you could write that out.
You could write it, as a C, half diminished seven.
Or C minor seven, flat five.
Or over here, C minor seven, flat five.